<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Rizwana Khan]]></title><description><![CDATA[A human being]]></description><link>https://rizwanakhan.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 22:56:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Analytical Engine]]></title><description><![CDATA[On #AdaLovelaceDay19: “How can I be concise, and accurate? How can I best pass along my intention, my information, to my readers?” (credits…]]></description><link>https://rizwanakhan.com/08-10-2019-analytical-engine/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://rizwanakhan.com/08-10-2019-analytical-engine/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 17:12:33 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/ada-letter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ada&apos;s Letter&quot; style=&quot;margin: 0px 0 40px; display: block; max-width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On #AdaLovelaceDay19:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How can I be concise, and accurate? How can I best pass along my intention, my information, to my readers?” &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://meghan-barrett.com/blog/2016/09/07/the-poetical-science-of-ada-lovelace/&quot;&gt;(credits)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn’t that the sole intention with which we pick up a pen to write? To measure into ounces, these thoughts our brains formulate into more lasting sentences? The above highlighted quote I stumbled upon in an article in which the author puts forth a case about how THE Ada Lovelace used both her insights into seeing poetry and science to, eventually, connect dots to a grander picture.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin-bottom:0;&quot;&gt;“If you can&apos;t give me poetry, can&apos;t you give me poetical science?”&lt;/h3&gt;  
-Ada
&lt;p&gt;Now, I’m no one to begin to understand Ada’s understanding of this world.
Her vision is one which, few, and certainly not I, could ever emulate or comment on. But her mention of poetical science found me transfixed as if an actual lightbulb in my brain had switched on.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is not a trivial trait for either a poet or a scientist to get to the heart of the matter simply, succinctly and successfully. These may be just the skills we need today”. It’s hard not to agree with Toole – poets and scientists are forever circling similar writing obstacles: how can I be concise, and accurate? How can I best pass along my intention, my information, to my readers? &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://meghan-barrett.com/blog/2016/09/07/the-poetical-science-of-ada-lovelace/&quot;&gt;(credits)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading this, I could not &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; smile. My eyes lit up. I’ve yet to meet a poet in the Tech industry. Perhaps, Ada was onto something more than &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; the Analytical Engine...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/ada-photo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ada&apos;s Photo&quot; style=&quot;margin: 40px auto 40px; display: block; max-width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-11:51PM&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Subpar]]></title><description><![CDATA[It’s been nice, frankly. Laying letters into a semblance of a blog post. I’ve ran into the act of writing something, anything, yet again…for…]]></description><link>https://rizwanakhan.com/04-10-2019-Subpar/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://rizwanakhan.com/04-10-2019-Subpar/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 17:12:33 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/view.png&quot; alt=&quot;Palm Trees&quot; style=&quot;margin: 0px 0 40px; display: block; max-width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been nice, frankly. Laying letters into a semblance of a blog post. I’ve ran into the act of writing something, anything, yet again…for good reason. A word of caution: This, I type, past midnight on a Friday and while I’m not particularly sleepy, the editor-in-me is more forgiving of subpar writing around this time.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been a week since Final Year of Uni began. As ridiculous as me worrying over the stress of deadlines sounds (hell, it’s a sign of my privilege that I get to rant on this particular #1stWorldProblem ), it’s rather difficult to un-worry? I know I ought to accept this as the norm. After all, we’re all drifting under different weights of worry at different times, whether or not we lay it out into words. That’s a shared comfort in any turmoil.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was #NationalPoetryDay and oh boy, how I loved it. Poetry’s slipped into my life and taken hold of so much of how these thoughts, untangle. And, its continued to remain a novel medium of self-expression after all this time. I’m still sure I do it right. See, I’ve never had someone teach it to me. Thus, I admit to calling myself a poet on material that may be as far away from poetry as the North and South poles, themselves.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even then, I chase its company.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To mark the occasion yesterday, I spammed the whole of Twitter with a million poetry-related tweets and likes and retweets. Here, I’ll share a duality with these 2 incredible poems.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maggie Smith’s &lt;em&gt;Good Bones&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/good-bones.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Maggie Smith’s Good Bones&quot; style=&quot;margin: 40px 0 40px; display: block; max-width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Danusha Lameris’s &lt;em&gt;Small Kindnesses&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/small-kindnesses.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Danusha Lameris’s Small Kindnesses&quot; style=&quot;margin: 40px 0 40px; display: block; max-width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of these poems unpacked, beautifully - a lasting feeling. I was better for having read them and I hope, maybe, even ONE of you reading them here⁠...now⁠, are, too?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finally, because I could not help myself:&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember, if you find a poet/poet-in-making around you:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome their words with them. Bring their meek, uncertain verses into the limelight. Ask them how troublesome their writing&apos;s been to them.&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;They&apos;ll shuffle their feet &amp;#x26; thank you in their heart, quietly.&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-2:23AM&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[tryin']]></title><description><![CDATA[Every so often, I take up a blank document and agree with my brain’s demands to pen some prose. See, I’ve gotten too comfortable by staring…]]></description><link>https://rizwanakhan.com/24-09-2019-tryin/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://rizwanakhan.com/24-09-2019-tryin/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 17:12:33 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/palms.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Palm Trees&quot; style=&quot;margin: 0px 0 40px; display: block; max-width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every so often, I take up a blank document and agree with my brain’s demands to pen some prose. See, I’ve gotten too comfortable by staring at blank documents, transforming these into written, wanna-be poems; leaving the discovering of the subject in the act of writing, itself. “This doesn’t work with prose”, I hear the outspoken, inner-voice of Rizwana The Self-Critic.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“..you gotta know what you wanna write about first, dummy”, it says without much a presence of any manners.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am reminded of a time I set out to write ‘quotes’. As a kid, I would read all these amazing words  (having searched for, for e.g., “Quotes on Time” , “ Quotes on Home” etc.), and think these were written by Quote Writers. Great authors who sat down perfecting their craft into quote-sized writings. A genre unlike any other!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rizwana The Self-Critic was cool with it/back then.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frankly, it was running into a blog post in which Someone Wonderful advised writing more blog posts that jolted my brain into doing this. Someone Wonderful writes words that are wonderful.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, I wanted to be able to do the same.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only how do I say things, clearly?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began this sentence comparing Clarity to chasing after the horizon. You understand why I had to erase that sentence. I can’t even describe Clarity without muddling it up with an elaborate picture of the horizon in a county with palm trees. Is this what you were promised, Reader?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this the kind of empty blog posts you had advised, Someone Wonderful?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are there so many questions?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fills just about half of my blank document. My brain at this point regrets this, entirely. Rizwana The Self-Critic consoles me, certain no one will read this. More surely so, if I bin this.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am reminded of a time in the future I might look back to this (maybe, Clarity, then, would be as simple as a giggle).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every so often, prose is the passerby in close quarters.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sorry, brain, I tried. I really did.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[🎙️ Rizamblings - Episode 7 (Some Snazzy Salads)]]></title><description><![CDATA[In which, I actually read you an essay. Plus, I dabble on final year of uni, what it means to be a perfectionist and salads that resemble…]]></description><link>https://rizwanakhan.com/23-09-2019-rizamblings-ep7/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://rizwanakhan.com/23-09-2019-rizamblings-ep7/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 17:12:33 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://pods.slantedpress.com/embed/3/d66a0cd3a688bb32d6b54745c73f2b48&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;160px&quot; style=&quot;border:none&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In which, I actually read you an essay. Plus, I dabble on final year of uni, what it means to be a perfectionist and salads that resemble some animals. A mixed bowl; as always.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&apos;t forget to #RizambleAlong on Twitter, find me -&gt; @rizbizkits&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[settlin']]></title><description><![CDATA[This is me typing into Visual Studio Code during lunch break in a Subway, around the corner:   I'm unsure why the muse bothered me on this…]]></description><link>https://rizwanakhan.com/10-09-2019-settlin/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://rizwanakhan.com/10-09-2019-settlin/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 17:12:33 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This is me typing into Visual Studio Code during lunch break in a Subway, around the corner:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&apos;m unsure why the muse bothered me on this occasion? I have nothing in particular to say
to you, Reader. Perhaps, it was, then, the prospect of settling in?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You see, I have this dome of Web Sorcery, decorated almost as nicely as my brain had pictured, all to myself. It&apos;s a new feeling; hosting your own words in a more honest voice than any other Medium.&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It&apos;s already led me to this sandwich franchise, made me want to say something to YOU.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Does one experience the same in a newly decorated room? Is a new coat of paint just as captivating? Or am I in the midst of something virtually unprecedented?&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Only now it wasn&apos;t even past noon. My lunch, too, is shortened.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was me typing into Visual Studio Code during lunch break in a Subway, around the corner.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[🎙️ Rizamblings - Episode 6 (For Lin-Manuel Miranda)]]></title><description><![CDATA[Our guest, (THE) Andrew Seward, rambles along us, making for the longest episode in Rizamblings history. We chat Hamilton, Hufflepuffs and…]]></description><link>https://rizwanakhan.com/09-09-2019-rizamblings-ep6/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://rizwanakhan.com/09-09-2019-rizamblings-ep6/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:12:33 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://pods.slantedpress.com/embed/3/bb9c2741f90f98144e0397438a47114b&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;160px&quot; style=&quot;border:none&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our guest, (THE) Andrew Seward, rambles along us, making for the longest episode in Rizamblings history. We chat Hamilton, Hufflepuffs and an extra SPECIAL, INSIDE SCOOP on Tech Nottingham from (the man, the myth, the legend) Andrew, himself.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find our guest, Andrew Seward -&gt; @MrAndrew  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&apos;t forget to #RizambleAlong on Twitter, find me -&gt; @rizbizkits&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[🎙️ Rizamblings - Episode 5 (Melting Into Potatoes)]]></title><description><![CDATA[This time we venture into some real talk, with particularly sporadic ramblings on humor, penguins, home etc. i also butcher the…]]></description><link>https://rizwanakhan.com/02-09-2019-rizamblings-ep5/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://rizwanakhan.com/02-09-2019-rizamblings-ep5/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 17:12:33 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://pods.slantedpress.com/embed/3/8d01e3064fbb49bda4d3d98500c362fb&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;160px&quot; style=&quot;border:none&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time we venture into some real talk, with particularly sporadic ramblings on humor, penguins, home etc. i also butcher the pronunciation of naivety...which is unsurprising.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&apos;t forget to #RizambleAlong on Twitter, find me -&gt; @rizbizkits&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[🎙️ Rizamblings - Episode 4 (Math By Mini Coopers) ft. Jonathan Relf]]></title><description><![CDATA[We have our 2nd Guest (and fellow podcaster!), rambling together on podcasting, creativity, buses etc. all whilst sitting in a noisy…]]></description><link>https://rizwanakhan.com/19-08-2019-rizamblings-ep4/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://rizwanakhan.com/19-08-2019-rizamblings-ep4/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 17:12:33 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://pods.slantedpress.com/embed/3/583e7db35de720146ceda5e12381889e&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;160px&quot; style=&quot;border:none&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have our 2nd Guest (and fellow podcaster!), rambling together on podcasting, creativity, buses etc. all whilst sitting in a noisy, neighborhood cafe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find our guest, Jonathan Relf -&gt; @jbjon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&apos;t forget to #RizambleAlong on Twitter, find me -&gt; @rizbizkits&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[🎙️ Rizamblings - Episode 3 (Dumpster Fire Experience) ft. Farhana Akmal]]></title><description><![CDATA[We have our first Guest (cough * my sister * cough) and so we ramble on a multitude of random topics ranging from Chernobyl to Spongebob…]]></description><link>https://rizwanakhan.com/31-07-2019-rizamblings-ep3/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://rizwanakhan.com/31-07-2019-rizamblings-ep3/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 17:12:33 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://pods.slantedpress.com/embed/3/91b1cb0edb43352d7c03c8679e86d3db&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;160px&quot; style=&quot;border:none&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have our first Guest (cough * my sister * cough) and so we ramble on a multitude of random topics ranging from Chernobyl to Spongebob...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&apos;t forget to #RizambleAlong on Twitter, find me -&gt; @rizbizkits &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Kay(e)’s in London — A Recap]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is my ramble-y recap of attending and volunteering for Sarah Kay and Phil Kaye Live in London, on 17th July, 2019. You ever looked at a…]]></description><link>https://rizwanakhan.com/25-07-2019-kayes/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://rizwanakhan.com/25-07-2019-kayes/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 17:12:33 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/poets.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Sarah and Phil Kaye on Stage&quot; style=&quot;margin: 10px 0; display: block; max-width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is my ramble-y recap of attending and volunteering for Sarah Kay and Phil Kaye Live in London, on 17th July, 2019.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You ever looked at a moment whilst in that moment and thought to yourself: &lt;em&gt;How will memory contain this? How will memory alone collect it? Oh, how can it keep the littlest details safe and special?&lt;/em&gt; Those specific questions I heard echoed back at me &lt;em&gt;(from wherever looming questions, as such, stem from)&lt;/em&gt; as I was sat, neck slightly tilted upwards, watching and listening to &lt;strong&gt;Sarah Kay&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Phil Kaye&lt;/strong&gt; reading their poems on a London stage, one humid Wednesday evening. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up as a third-culture kid in Saudi Arabia, school was a mixed cuisine buffet. My Palestinian/Jordanian best friend and I, mimicked our Indian teachers’ funny ways of saying some words &lt;em&gt;(ironically enough)&lt;/em&gt; using our own odd, hybrid palette of accents and words. A palette we made, borrowing from each other amidst growing up in this home that was as foreign to us as was also &lt;em&gt;ours&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One you only ever can build together. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, even in such a short-lasting, sense of permanence, the love for Sarah and Phil was a given. Videos on Youtube of both of them performing their spoken-word wonders was watched and adored by so many of my school friends, even ones for whom poetry was a passable thing, it became a timeless, tangible language of admiration we continue to speak even after all this time, having collected our palettes into separate suitcases to homes in different countries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, for July to come around and for me to be the first of my school to be stood in front of a red door was &lt;em&gt;(and now I hope you begin to understand..)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;profound&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For out walked, Phil, long-haired, tall and all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I tried to crack a joke or something about having to now stare at him while climbing these steep stairs because obviously I was unprepared for this moment. I’m not sure how much of said joke was imparted, to the confines outside my own brain. Either way, I remembered to breathe..which helped with self-survival, if we’re being totally frank. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;side-note: He does this thing where he says ‘Hi, I’m Phil’ and, I don’t know about the others, but my gut instinct, instead of saying the sensible ‘Hi, I’m Riz’, is to reply with a ‘Duh! 👏 You’re 👏 Phil 👏 Kaye’.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I had begun to recover from this sudden Phil appearance, my return to a general, calmer self was cut short, as Sarah casually waved from near the end steps of this gigantic theatre room where I and the other volunteers were ushered into, and I, kid you not, I could not wipe this smile &lt;em&gt;(definitely a size much larger than the room)&lt;/em&gt; from my face. Hell, even the Joker would be taking lessons from ME with my smile that wide. I remember thinking, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“who let me be this happy?”&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, it’s because I’ve never met anyone famous. Once, during a rather tiring stopover before our flight to Pakistan, my father shook hands with our country’s cricketing Legend (and now, Prime Minister..), &lt;em&gt;Imran Khan&lt;/em&gt;. I woke up from Airport-caused slumber, moments after he had walked away. And while I wasn’t particularly ever a fan of his, it would be incorrect of me to say I wasn’t disappointed at this missed crossing. So, meeting Phil and Sarah was much like running before walking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a crossing I had expected to be a quick hello. This, too, would’ve been more than enough for me. But when the moment came, I did not envision it to feel like I hadn’t just met these two mega poetry celebrities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See, sheepishly, I introduced myself to Sarah. &lt;em&gt;“I’m Riz”&lt;/em&gt;, I wanted to make sure I didn’t mumble as I often do in situations when my heart beats out of my chest. She recognizes me from Twitter, think she even calls me(!) her(!!!) Twitter friend. And as she talks us through our volunteering roles, she calls me Riz. Sure, I’ve only met two famous people in my life by now but that’s besides the point. Sarah, for the rest of the evening, remembers my name. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She didn’t have to but she does, anyway. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;side-note: She does this thing where, when people tell her their names for a signature on their books, Sarah will try and guess the correct name spellings, out loud. Every time she it right (and she got it right, many times..), the joy on her face is visible and infectious from miles away.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maybe it’s humility, after all, that keeps you grounded.&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the show begins with with a sold-out 700(?) audience under this one roof, sweating, yes, but &lt;strong&gt;excited&lt;/strong&gt;, the applause that erupts as our poets now walk out on stage, lasts a long time. When they take this crowd &lt;em&gt;(and at this point, the room doesn’t feel big at all)&lt;/em&gt;, from poem to poem, sharing laughter, hurt, awe, and feelings, in a way I have no words for, I constantly strive for just the simple thing:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To take it in. To look so intently, so earnestly, I would not have to rely on memory alone. To, somehow, hold &lt;strong&gt;this&lt;/strong&gt; exact time, as long and as dearly, it could endure anything life would choose from its treasure chest of woes for me.
To, were I to look back, be convinced that I cherished (and tended to) my heart made happy by these poets’ hearts and their art.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Always&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;em&gt;All Ways&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It is too easy to spend all your time worried about the hurt that could be on its way. You’ll miss the moon rising over the orchard in the meantime. Don’t miss it, friend. How lucky you are that for even just tonight, you have twice as many stars in your sky.&quot;
— S. Kay  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, in case, I failed this simple task, I travelled back &lt;em&gt;(in probably a bit of a delirious state)&lt;/em&gt;, from London to Nottingham, on a cheap coach booked for past-midnight on the same day, accepting:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/riz-&amp;-the-poets.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Sarah and Phil Kaye on Stage&quot; style=&quot;margin: 50px auto; display: block; max-width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I would wake from this one, any moment.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[🎙️ Rizamblings - Episode 2 (Saltpots & Soundpicks)]]></title><description><![CDATA[RizambleAlong -> hashtag activated. This podcast needs YOU and YOUR decisive brains, metaphorically speaking...of course. (p.s. take a shot…]]></description><link>https://rizwanakhan.com/14-07-2019-rizamblings-ep2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://rizwanakhan.com/14-07-2019-rizamblings-ep2/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 17:12:33 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://pods.slantedpress.com/embed/3/f3b4ebdf0fd2a815e55988d0655d8244&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;160px&quot; style=&quot;border:none&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;RizambleAlong -&gt; hashtag activated.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This podcast needs YOU and YOUR decisive brains, metaphorically speaking...of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(p.s. take a shot every time i say &apos;AND&apos; ðŸ˜…)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter: @rizbizkits &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Beyond Them 20s.]]></title><description><![CDATA[So I’m writing this on the train back to Nottingham from Lincoln. A journey I undertook 5 days a week for the past year. And while I’ve…]]></description><link>https://rizwanakhan.com/29-06-2019-beyond-them-20s/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://rizwanakhan.com/29-06-2019-beyond-them-20s/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 17:12:33 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;So I’m writing this on the train back to Nottingham from Lincoln. A journey I undertook 5 days a week for the past year. And while I’ve begun writing this today I doubt I would ever be able to finish it in one sitting, much less finish it at all. There’s already a multitude of thoughts in the bucket of a brain that belongs to me and when you introduce the presence of an ending into it, well, then I could ramble around what I actually want to write for forever and, in Liam Neeson style, you will have to find me…and you will have to stop me.
I rarely ever do introspective writing so openly. I’m a poet. Poets bury themselves in the collective, right?! But this one is far too important for poetic ambiguity. It would be proud of me not to at least recognize and appreciate when life doesn’t give you lemons (is that how idioms work?). When life seems to be on your side. Gratitude is best voiced out loud and this is my humble undertaking to do just that.
The last year for me has been one that, as a recently-turned-21 year old, I will hold dearly. While not perfect (life is designed outside a perfect narrative), it’s been truly transformative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I accepted my placement at Cursor in June, 2018 (a day after my 20th birthday), I was wholly excited and equally unprepared. I missed my train on the second day. I hated walking (I still hate walking). Hell, all I knew about the word ‘Lincoln’ was Abraham Lincoln (and I barely know much about Abraham Lincoln either..). After the first week ended, I was already shattered. I stressed over how much I didn’t know, how much I felt like I really was an imposter sitting next to a brilliant team who would always know more than I ever could. I might have even counted the exact number of weeks that awaited until the end. I simply could not believe how much longer there was to go.
Then, days began to change themselves. The commute was never easy, especially in the two stuffed carriages that were consistently worsening. The four hours I got to spend awake at home were never enough for anything. Yet, I settled into the routine and, somehow, perhaps miraculously,grew to find firmer ground to stand on. (fun fact: I even bought my very own Poundland mug for the occasional tea in the office, until that mug transformed into a vessel for up to 4 coffees a day as the days piled on. So hip.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cursor Team
Without a doubt, each member of the team was paramount to this growth I had never expected or envisioned. And while there were challenges, deadlines, and mistakes, there was also laughter, mentoring, and pancakes!
For the opportunity of spending my time in the company of such a team, was a highlight of my year and I thank each Pointer (that’s my proposed name for everyone who works at Cursor, think similar to Beliebers for Justin Bieber? It’s very much still awaiting team approval..) MOST sincerely. (Special mention to Nick for baking a helluva HTML+CSS birthday cake and Daniel for turning my last lunch in the office into a birthday team meal. That was a special kind of special).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;like, how cool is this?
Besides my placement at Cursor, another thing that happened in the last year that changed my life: a crazy invitation to write and read out a poem, my poem, at New Adventures 2019, in front of the largest audience I have stood on a stage looking onto. I could pen novels fathoming exactly how precious that moment has become to me but instead you’ll only have to go by this blog post and believe that, even today, my mind is filled with awe and gratitude when I think back to it.
I’m now continuing writing this long after I originally started. It’s a Saturday and I’m contemplating what awaits ahead. See, opportunities are funny things. When you avail one, they still seem like a distant dream…until it’s suddenly time and you find yourself lifted in their whirlwind of an excitement but also sheer disbelief. That’s what I’m fortunate to be feeling today. For 2 reasons.
First of which happens to be the fact that I’ll officially be joining the splendid JH agency as a Design Intern for the summer. &lt;em&gt;yay&lt;/em&gt; There’s so much I will undoubtedly learn and thus, I will be documenting this journey in my writing as best I can for you all (especially for those early in their Tech careers like myself. We’re all in this together ← yes, that’s a High School Musical reference thank you very much.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second reason warms my heart beyond measure.
July, 4th might be an important date for America but its become an even more important date to me. Women in Tech, Nottingham is a local community that has, without being dramatic, changed my life. To take up their stage on Thursday, July, 4th, and deliver my first full length talk, titled No Time to Spare: Spark, Tinder, Breeze, is akin to coming home after a long, tiring day. No matter how well the jokes in my talk land on the day or just how much I ramble, I know I will be in the company of my people. That, alone, is accolade enough for me.
So, yeah. That’s that on turning 21. I know I’m supposed to write something wholly pensive or concise now to wrap this up, beautifully. But that, even at 21, is a talent I’ve yet to tackle.
Perhaps, next year?
4&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[🎙️ Rizamblings - Episode 1 (Shaky Beginnings)]]></title><description><![CDATA[So, yeah? We're doing this.
The Announcement, some Introduction, and my mumble-y voice. Like, what more could you want..right?!]]></description><link>https://rizwanakhan.com/27-06-2019-rizamblings-ep1/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://rizwanakhan.com/27-06-2019-rizamblings-ep1/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 17:12:33 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://pods.slantedpress.com/embed/3/377edfc467b457d922414534f896cc34&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;160px&quot; style=&quot;border:none&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yeah? We&apos;re doing this.
The Announcement, some Introduction, and my mumble-y voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like, what more could you want..right?!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[My New Adventures 2019]]></title><description><![CDATA[Let’s be straight: I’ve never, ever recapped conferences.
Words are a messy alternate to the multitude of GIFs that I find, express my most…]]></description><link>https://rizwanakhan.com/31-01-2019-new-adventures/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://rizwanakhan.com/31-01-2019-new-adventures/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 17:12:33 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Let’s be straight: I’ve never, ever recapped conferences.
Words are a messy alternate to the multitude of GIFs that I find, express my most sincere feelings in a much natural way. Whether that’s because I’m 20 and thus influenced by my Millennial Tendencies or because I need help — remains a mystery.
(Here’s real, proper recaps instead of this mess of a mess that I am writing. Here, here, here and here. I urge you go read those. Get Clickity Clicking...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
But yes. New Adventures. What an authentically surreal moment in time. 
&lt;p&gt;I remember scrolling through my Twitter feed a while before the conference when I unknowingly landed on the New Adventures twitter account and first read about this unusually named thing that was apparently Notts-based. Enough to say, I never could have imagined how something so unknown would leave such an impact on me. #cheesy i know, but 100% truth.
My Adventure
The butterfly-in-stomach feeling for me at New Adventures was this bizarre thing where I, a person with 0 conference talks, was somehow to walk on stage and read, out loud, words that I had written in my morning train commute. Words I had sent back to Simon, with a funny, certain uncertainty that he would kindly have to refuse them:
words I had audacity to call poetry. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoilers: He didn’t refuse. Initially, it was only going to be a poem written to be printed in the stellar magazine which basically left me dumbstruck for a good 72 hours but then somehow, I think, Simon’s brain was struck with this wacky, outlandish idea that he ought to get me to read it on stage, too? The same stage that had a roster of brilliant, accomplished speakers that have careers lasting longer than the number of years I have been on this planet(!) Trust me, incredulous is a word too sparse in describing what I felt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, to provide an opportunity and a platform to someone, especially someone totally unheard of, is an act of showcasing that you have trust in them and their voice. Simon’s shown just that. And if there’s anyone out there who’s in the similar shoes, whether they be like mine or Simon’s, please know: New Adventures is exemplary; you have to be brave to know people will listen to your voice and you have reach out to trusting people’s voices, if given the chance. If you do that, then believe me, you will be like confetti in that someone’s life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;credits: Stefan Nitzsche
(Another ‘Thank you, Simon. Truly’ is long overdue.)
Shared Adventures
Now that I have splat out what I felt from my side, I do have to reiterate the sheer wisdom of the talks. The many quick, scribbled notes and shaky images of the slides that excited-me was busy collecting, amid being totally engrossed during each of the talk, is proof there’s loads I have to learn and have learnt. My favorite speakers include Jeremy Keith, Clare Sutcliffe, Josh Brewer, M̶o̶r̶n̶i̶n̶g̶ ̶B̶r̶e̶a̶k̶, Jessica White, Ashley Baxter, Brenden Dawes, Helen Joy, A̶f̶t̶e̶r̶n̶o̶o̶n̶ ̶B̶r̶e̶a̶k̶, Naz Hamid and Ethan Marcotte.
Each of them shared a piece of their wisdom, wit and wonder. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lack the sophistication to summarize what they presented without botching it. But if you’re curious (&amp;#x26; you ought to be) then make sure you watch the videos once they are magically uploaded or give the speakers‘ twitters cheeky follows to keep an 👁️ out for where they could be speaking next.
(Also, the Women in Tech Lightning Talks were most fun! Not only because I completely 💖 Lightning Talks but also because I completely 💖 The Loveliest WiTNotts community)
New New Adventures
Let’s lay a fact: conferences are scary beasts to organize. The most traumatic gathering that I can remember arranging (more like had my parents arrange..) was my (i think) 7th birthday that was canceled because, like, only one kid agreed to show up. How rude.
Regardless, 7 year old me understood that day, that people and events can be cruel and unpredictable and, sometimes, leave you with the expenses of unlit, birthday candles weighing you down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How that saddening story has anything to do with New Adventures is a fine question and one which I will answer, lacking all the finesse in the world. Ok, here goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it’s an analogy! or a metaphor! or neither! or both!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I imagine Simon might have similar feelings of fear and dread of the Conference Beast, I can assure you, and him (Hi, Simon!) — as a first-time attendee — his gathering, despite the tribulations in organizing, was, without question, a roaring success.
I can only wish him the best of luck to continue. Especially in the face of annoying suppliers, unsold tickets, and bills-that-even-my-two-kidneys-will-not-pay-for.
To persist.
For transforming a room with a giant organ in the backdrop, is an adventure of many, many, many lifetimes.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>